BRANDON DEATON

Security Analyst

(702) 480-1592

Coeur D'Alene, ID



https://linkedin.com/in/brandondeaton1993



https://enjoiy.vercel.app

Summary

I am an enthusiastic and initiative-taking security analyst. Secured a strong academic background in software development, having graduated with a 4.0 from the College of Western Idaho. Two years have been devoted in full-stack web applications, data integration, and design collaboration. This programming mindset is being used to help advance into the career of cyber security. These efforts drive activity in seeking out a challenging and rewarding position within a security team to learn new skills and evolve in both the solo and team setting.

Skills

Languages

- ◆ C#
- ♦ Python
- ♦ SQL
- ♦ HTML | CSS | JavaScript

- **Tools**Wireshark | tcpdump
- SIEM tools
- ♦ NumPy
- Pandas

os

- Debian | Ubuntu
- Windows
- MacOS
- ♦ iOS | Android

Experience

Sales Support Specialist

Remote

Clearlight Infrared Saunas

May 2024 - Current

- Assist with Sales Support team to locate buried hot leads and provide a second point of contact to ensure their requests are fulfilled.
- ♦ Utilize CRM software (Keap, NetSuite, Podium) to drive productivity and increase lead generation.
- Expanded skills in team collaboration, administrative, and communication.

Software Development Tutor

Nampa, ID

College of Western Idaho

Jan. 2024 – May 2024

- Position offered through a recommendation by the 2nd year professor.
- Helped tutor a class of 19 students learn the fundamentals of C#/Windows Forms and web development using HTML5/CSS3.
- Skilled in collaborating with the teacher to find more effective ways to communicate concepts and code.

Web Designer

Remote

MindHome

May 2023 – Aug. 2023

- ♦ Collaborated with a team of 3 to create web layouts and creative designs through Figma and transferred to builder.io (standard HTML).
- Acquired methodical experience in the agile development cycle.
- Developed skill and knowledge in designing two core web pages, 'Service Home' and 'Smart Home', hosted on the official site: mindhome.co.

Freelance Web Developer

Remote

Clearlight Infrared Saunas

Jan. 2023 – Jan. 2023

- Built an upload feature for users to submit their own measurements to the custom design team using JavaScript and HTML.
- Researched and implemented best practices for JavaScript development.
- Handled testing for the entire project and guaranteed 100% functionality.

Branch Manager Arlington, TX

Final Mile Solar Sept. 2019 – Jan. 2022

- Provided exemplary customer and client satisfaction through open communication and safety-first services handling solar panel deliveries.
- Obtained comprehensive experience in managing, training, warehousing, communication, DEI.
- Skilled in field training, planning, coordinating, and executing all aspects of the delivery process.

Education

Google Cybersecurity Remote

Certificate Sept. 2024

- ♦ Develop essential skills to protect devices, networks, and data using SIEM tools
- ♦ Advance my knowledge in SQL, Python, and Linux using isolated environments
- Learn to identify common threats, risks, and vulnerabilities and techniques to mitigate them
- Understand of the importance of cybersecurity practices and their impact on organizations

College of Western Idaho

Nampa, ID

A.A.S in Software Development | Summa Cum Laude

May 2024

- ♦ Client-Side Frameworks Comprehensive application of client-side scripting tech and frameworks. Emphasis is placed on creating UI and connecting software components (ReactJS, VueJS, Vite, Svelte).
- ♦ Collaborative Development Class introduction to formal test strategies, collaborative tools, and project management. Our capstone project was developed using modern scrum practices (Jira project mgmt., ASP.NETMVC, SQL Server). I played the role of UI/UX developer that served as the color palette and layout standard designer.
- Advanced Web App Development Exploring dynamic websites focusing on e-commerce and server-side scripting (SQL Server, SQLite3, and ASP.NET Core MVC).

Cherry Creek High School
Diploma

Greenwood Village, CO May 2011

Additional Skills | Achievements

- ♦ Earned 3 certifications through College of Western Idaho via PearsonVUE Certiport. Python, SQL databases, and HTML5 application development.
- ♦ Advanced proficiency in operating Windows, Linux command line, WSL, VMs, MacOS, and iOS.
- Threats, risks, and vulnerabilities
- ♦ Incident response
- ♦ Security frameworks and controls
- ♦ SIEM tools
- Problem-solving.
- Discipline.
- ♦ Adaptability.
- ♦ Team player.